# **GEORGE EFTICHIOU**

#### **CONTACT INFORMATION**



+357 96452718



<u>eftichiou@hotmail.com</u>



https://www.geef.cc

## **EDUCATION**

#### Self-Taught Coding | 2019-2021

During this period, I've spent a significant amount of time learning primarily from Udemy, focusing on JavaScript, React, Node, js, Next. js, CSS

# Intercollege, Larnaca, Cyprus | 2009-2011 Computer Science Higher Diploma Programming Courses:

- Visual Basic Programming
- C++ Programming
- Pascal Programming
- Cobol Programming
- Assembly Programming
- Database Creation and Analysis

Agios Georgios High School, Larnaca, Cyprus | 2004-2006 Computer Science

# **Experience With**

- JavaScript
- Typescript
- React.js
- Next.js
- Node.js
- Redux
- CSS (SASS & Styled Components & Modules)
- Web Components (Stencil.js)
- Webpack
- Rest APIs
- Docker
- Kubernetes & OpenShift
- Git & Jira & Jenkins

## **Hobby Technologies**

- Java
- SQL & Hibernate
- AWS
- React NativeRust
- Noct i
- Nest.js
- Nginx
- Phaser.js & Three.js
- WebSocket (Socket.io & Netty)
- MongoDB

## Languages

- Greek (Native)
- English (Fluent)
- Russian (Basic)

#### **Traits**

- Learn Enthusiast
- Team Player
- Multi-Tasking

#### References

Available on Request

#### PERSONAL PROFILE

Having worked extensively with frontend applications coupled with my professional certifications I have gained exposure and established various technical skills relating to web developing. A proactive, self-motivated individual, with strong learning enthusiasm. I relish the opportunity to work as part of a team, enjoying the challenge of taking on new roles and responsibilities in dynamic working environments.

## **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

## **Amdocs**

2022 - Today | Cyprus, Limassol Advance Software Developer

Developed and maintained scalable front-end applications using React, Redux, TypeScript. Wrote mocking endpoints using Node.js and Express.js, ensuring seamless REST integration. Collaborated with backend teams to integrate APIs, optimize data handling, and improve system performance. Implemented best practices for state management, UI performance, and reusable component structures. Conducted code reviews and provided technical mentorship to junior developers. Worked closely with product owners and UX/UI designers to improve user experience.

## **Cypos Systems**

2021 – 2022 | Cyprus, Limassol Software Developer

Built web applications using Next.js, leveraging both server-side rendering and client-side rendering to optimize performance and user experience. Created and implemented webhooks with Node.js to integrate third-party APIs, ensuring seamless data synchronization and communication between systems.

Career Transition Self-Taught Coding | 2019 - 2021

### PROJECTS & CONTRIBUTIONS

#### **Amdocs**

- SRM (Resource Management System): A system designed for efficient resource management within telecommunication companies.
- NEF (Network Exposure Function): An application facilitating secure API exposure, enhancing connectivity and automation in network operations.

#### Foody & Cypos

Foody Delivery Platform and ICG Solutions integration that allows the POS software of ICG to communicate during online transaction made on Foody platform. The project is using Typescript on NodeJS (Express) server on AWS cluster implementing Nginx Load Balancing in case an instance goes down. The API bridge code uses asynchronous concurrency for API calls to use NodeJS asynchronous I/O non-blocking capabilities.

#### Other

- An eCommerce application built with a Node.js backend and a React/Next.js frontend, integrated with Stripe for payments. The frontend is deployed on Vercel, while the backend runs on AWS with MongoDB hosted on MongoDB Atlas. This project was developed as a learning experience.
- A web application built with Java Spring Boot and Netty (Socket.io) for WebSocket communication, allowing multiple users to log in via the Next.js frontend. Users can synchronize their items in real time through the app's UI and chat. The project utilizes SQL and Hibernate for data management.